Takoradi

0265257177 / 0200588427

abaodum@gmail.com

ABA ESUON ODUM

OBJECTIVE

An independent and self-motivated professional with excellent research skills; able to grow positive relationships with clients and colleagues at all organizational levels and an organized, detail oriented, and conscientious self-starter, able to strategize and prioritize effectively to accomplish multiple tasks and consistently meet deadlines.

SKILLS & ABILITIES

- Programming Languages: php, c sharp,asp.net, javascript, html5,
 css3, jquery, ajax,, java, angular js,nodejs
- Databases: MYSQL, Oracle, MSSQL, MS Access, SAP HANA, Couchdb
- Tools: Eclipse, Netbeans, PhpStorm, Visual Studio, .
- Others: Strong knowledge of the software life cycle, system analysis, software Engineering, Networking and use of web services and rest apis.

EDUCATION

KWAME NKRUMAH UNIVERSITY OF SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY, KUMASI

Bachelor of Computer Science - August 2010 - June 2014

TARKWA SECONDARY SCHOOL, TARKWA, WESTERN REGION

General Science -September 2006 - May 2009

BETHEL METHODIST SCHOOL, TAKORADI, WESTERN REGION

1996 - 2006

EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE ENGINEER, GCB LIMITED

February 2018 - Current date

Leveraging the banks technology infrastructure through software engineers and other skills to provide value for internal and external customers. Example integration with 3rd parties, product development, supporting technology infrastructure.

- Developed Payments and Collections System (Revenue Collection 3rd Parties e.g Databank, School fees ,churches) used at all GCB Branches).
- 2. Research Archives System(Accessed by all staff to download bank policies and other documents(financial news, exchange and treasury bill rates).

- 3. Remit Direct(Transferring funds from MTOs straight into GCB customers accounts)
- 4. Merchant Portal used by our 3rd Parties to monitor their transactions and spool reports.
- 5. Transaction Portal (used my management to monitor all transactions)

SOFTWARE ENGINEER, CAPITAL BANK

January 2017 – August 2017

Leveraging the banks technology infrastructure through software engineers and other skills to provide value for internal and external customers. Example integration with 3rd parties, product development, supporting technology infrastructure.

- 1. Develop software solutions by understanding customer(both internal and external) needs;conferring with customers and users;studying systems flow,data usage and work processes;investigating problem areas;following the Bank's software development lifecycle.
- 2. Provide support across all channels in the area of product development and redesign to improve existing products/services of the bank.
- 3. Work with Third Party Service Providers to integrate their systems with the bank in line with IT policies/procedures and service standards.
- 4. Work closely with Analysts,IT/Software Designers,Sales/Marketing and Research teams to translate ideas/concepts of proposed product innovation to reality.
- 5. Provide support in innovative approach to service delivery in the Bank.

WEB DEVELOPER AND DATABASE ADMINISTRATOR, VODAFONE

November 2015 – December 2016

- 1. Breaking down program specification into its simplest elements and translating logic into a programming language.
- 2. Designing new database (Oracle) application based on the requirement and specifications.
- 3. Creating stored procedures, indexes, sequences, constraints, schemas, triggers, functions and custom queries on the database created.
- 4. Exposing the database and all the views created for front end development.
- 5. Exporting database content to any specified files (e.g. excel, pdf, word, csv).
- 6. Developing administration panel on the database for any report generations.
- 7. Develop software, user interfaces and client displays.
- 8. Deliver and test software prototypes.
- 9. Creating web services to serve as communication medium between the database and the front end application.
- 10. Coordinate with other team developers.

WEB DEVELOPER, TRASH RECYCLING AND WASTE MANAGEMENT ORGANIZATION (PART TIME)

September 2014 –July 2015

- 1. Developed and maintained internal and external company Web sites.
- 2. Manage projects and contribute to committee or team work.
- 3. Coordinate with other team members.

TEACHING ASSISTANT, KWAME NKRUMAH UNIVERSITY OF SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY (NATIONAL SERVICE)

August 2014 – July 2015

- 1. Taught introduction to database programming.
- 2. Taught Computer Security.
- 3. Taught Networking. 6. Programming for mobile applications (android, ios). 5. Lead discussion sections, tutorials, or laboratory sections.

NETWORK ADMINISTRATOR, TIMBER INDUSTRY AND DEVELOPMENT DIVISION (INTERN)

June 2012 – August 2012 1. basic networking

- 1. Troubleshooting computers
- 2.IP Addressing

PERSONAL ACHIEVEMENT

1. Built Centralized Authentication System at Capital Bank, Staff used Active Directory credentials to log into internal applications

- 2. Built Transaction Portal to monitor all transactions that happens across all channels(web,ussd,mobile,banking hall) in the Bank.
- 3. Built Operations Management System to aid in clearing process.
- 4. Built Payments and Collections Management System to be used by tellers in the banking hall.(services i.e ecg postpaid,mastercard,gip)
- 5. Built Attendance Management System to check attendance of staff across all branches.(description; data is spooled from clocks and uploaded into the system,the system flags staff that report late and leaves early)
- 6. Built User Management System; developers register applications and its permissions into the applications, staff are assigned permissions to individual applications.
- 7. GIP integration; designed restful apis to be integrated across our channels.
- 8. ECG integration, designed restful apis to be consumed by our third parties.
- 9. Test Ghana

A web Application to aid teachers in learning and teaching children.

www.testghana.org

10. Amplifies Ghana

A web application for monitoring and reporting (www.amplifiesghana.org)

11. iShop

An ecommerce website for buying and selling phones and other accessories.

www.ishopelectronis.net

12. Other Corporate Websites

LEADERSHIP

- Computer Science Secretary April 2012 March 2013
 (Kwame Nkrumah University of Science and Technology)
- College of Science Board Member(Senator) April 2012 March 2013
 (Kwame Nkrumah University Of Science And Technology)

REFERENCES

PAPA KWAME ANANE

Unit Head, Product Development and Innovation

Capital Bank

0501296539

papa@greyparrot.io

DR. MICHAEL ASANTE

Head Of Department

Kwame Nkrumah University Of Science And Technology

020-8168613

mickasst@yahoo.com

DR.YAW MISSAH

Lecturer

Kwame Nkrumah University Of Science And Technology

0546399778

ymissah@gmail.com